Cody Baker

cody@codyrobert.com | (503) 270-7628

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/codyrobert/ | Portfolio: https://codyrobert.com/

Summary

Experienced Full Stack Software Engineer with over 20 years in web development. Proven ability to lead development teams, mentor junior developers, and deliver high-traffic, resilient web applications. Strong skills in JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, React, and various CMS platforms. Recognized for exceptional problem-solving abilities and strong communication skills.

Professional Experience

Principal Software Engineer, Flickerbox

July 2022 - Present

- Led the successful development of high-traffic CMS based websites on a global scale for leading companies in revenue intelligence, mobile app experience, identity access management, and employee background checks.
- Collaborated with leadership and design teams to prioritize objectives, resulting in improved organizational outcomes.
- Mentored and trained newly hired developers, simplifying technical concepts to accelerate their ability to produce valuable work.

Senior Full Stack Engineer, Flickerbox

Jan 2019 - July 2022

- Developed efficient and resilient backend and frontend frameworks for numerous client sites, serving 750000+ users each month.
- Implemented technical standards that guided the daily activities of a team of eight developers.
- Collaborated with internal and external teams to successfully execute redesign projects within budget and time constraints.

Full Stack Engineer, Flickerbox

Jan 2015 - Jan 2019

- Contributed to various client projects, enhancing website performance and user experience.
- Implemented new features and maintained existing codebases with a focus on scalability and resilience.

Web Developer, Joslex

Aug 2009 - Jan 2015

- Developed and maintained websites for various clients, improving functionality and user experience.
- Utilized a range of technologies including PHP, JavaScript, and WordPress, to deliver custom web solutions.

Freelance Web Developer, Self-employed

Nov 2002 - Aug 2009

• Provided web development services to various clients, delivering projects on time and within budget.

Skills

- Front-end & Frameworks: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Vue.js, Node.js, NPM, CSS, SCSS, HTML
- Backend & CMS: PHP, WordPress, Drupal, Laravel, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Education

Portland State University

Coursework in Computer Science 2006-2010

Recommendations

"Cody always exceeded my expectations. Not only was Cody easy to work with, he also had great communication and is one of the most talented programmers I've worked with. I'm confident he would be a great team player in any environment."

- Ryan Glasgow, CEO at Sprig

"Someone was looking at your code and told me you are a genius – I can't agree more! Thank you for all your help with everything, we couldn't have made all this progress without your help."

- Hamza Essaoui, Director, Web Development at Databricks